purdueglobal.edu 2019-09-09

# Privacy Policy - Purdue Global

## Privacy Policy

### **Last Updated: April, 2018**

This is the Privacy Policy for Purdue University Global (the "Site"), which is operated by Purdue University Global and managed by Kaplan Higher Education, LLC. ("Purdue Global," "we," or "us"). This Privacy Policy applies to the Site and not to other websites or services operated by Purdue Global or its subsidiaries or affiliates.

Purdue Global respects the privacy of our users and has developed this Privacy Policy to demonstrate its commitment to protecting your privacy. This privacy policy (the "Privacy Policy") is intended to describe for you, as an individual who is a user of Site, the information we collect, how that information may be used, with whom it may be shared, and your choices about such uses and disclosures. This Privacy Policy applies only to the Site and not to other websites or services operated by Purdue Global or its subsidiaries or affiliates.

We encourage you to read this Privacy Policy carefully when using our Site or services or transacting business with us. By using the Site, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy.

If you have any questions about our privacy practices, please refer to the end of this Privacy Policy for information on how to contact us.

### Express Consent to Receive Text Messages

If you have provided prior express written consent in the process of requesting information from Purdue Global about its educational offerings or services, or if you have provided prior express consent after becoming a student to receive texts, we may use text messages to communicate with you.

#### PurdueG

Text INFO to PURDUE (787383) to join PurdueG. The number of messages may vary. **Message and Data Rates May Apply**.Texts may be sent using an automatic telephone dialing system. Consent to receive marketing text messages is not required as a condition of purchasing any goods or services.

#### STOP Information

Text STOP to PURDUE (787383) to stop receiving PurdueG messages from Purdue Global.

#### HELP Information

For additional information, text HELP to PURDUE (787383) or contact infopg@purdueglobal.edu or call 1-844-PURDUEG.

#### Carriers Supported

Compatible carriers include: AT&T, Sprint, T-Mobile®, Verizon Wireless, Boost, Cricket, MetroPCS, U.S. Cellular, Virgin Mobile, ACS Wireless, Appalachian Wireless, Bluegrass Cellular, Breakaway Wireless, Cablevision (Optimum Mobile), Carolina West Wireless, Cellcom, Cellular One of East Central Illinois, Centennial Wireless, Chariton Valley Cellular, Chat Mobility (Hawkeye), Cincinnati Bell Wireless, Coral Wireless, Cox Mobility, Cross/ Sprocket, C-Spire Wireless (formerly Cellsouth), CTC Telecom, DTC Wireless (Advantage Cellular), Duet IP (AKA Max/Benton/Albany), Element Mobile, Epic Touch, GCI Communications, Golden State, Illinois Valley Cellular, Immix (Keystone Wireless/ PC Management), Inland Cellular, iWireless, Leaco, Mobi PCS, Mosaic, MTPCS/ Cellular One (Cellone Nation), Nemont, Nex-Tech Wireless, nTelos, NW Missouri Cellular (Hawkeye), Panhandle Telecommunications, Peoples Wireless, Pioneer, Pine Cellular, Plateau, Revol, Rina - Custer, Rina - All West, Rina - Cambridge Telecom Coop, Rina - Eagle Valley Comm, Rina - Farmers Mutual Telephone Co, Rina - Nucla Nutria Telephone Co, Rina - Silver Star, Rina - Syringa, Rina - UBET, Rina - Manti, Rural Cellular Corporation, SI Wireless, Simmetry, SouthernLINC, SRT, Strata Networks, Thumb Cellular, Union Wireless, United, Viaero Wireless, West Central Wireless.

T-Mobile is not liable for delayed or undelivered messages.

**Information We Collect About You**

**In General**. We may collect personal information that can identify you, such as your name and email address, and other information that does not identify you. When you provide personal information to us, the information may be sent to servers located in the United States and other countries around the world.

**Information you provide**. We may collect and store any personal information you provide to us, including personal information that may be contained in any video, comment or other submission you upload or post to the Site. This includes identifying information, such as your name, address, e-mail address, and telephone number; your likeness; and, if you transact business with us, financial information such as your payment method (valid credit card number, type, expiration date or other financial information). We also may request information about your interests and activities, your gender and age, and other demographic information.

**Information from other sources.** We may also periodically obtain both personal and non-personal information about you from other Purdue Global businesses, business partners, contractors and other third parties. Examples of information that we may receive include: updated delivery and address information, purchase history, and additional demographic information.

**Information collected automatically**. We automatically collect information from your browser when you visit our Site. This information includes your IP address, your browser type and language, access times, the content of any undeleted cookies that your browser previously accepted from us (see "Cookies" below), and the referring website address.

**Cookies**.  We use various technologies to collect information from your computer and about your use of the Site. When you visit our website, we may assign your computer one or more cookies, to facilitate access to our site and to personalize your online experience. Through the use of a cookie, we also may automatically collect information about your online activity on our site, such as the web pages you visit, the links you click, and the searches you conduct on our Site. Most browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies. If you choose to decline cookies, please note that you may not be able to sign in or use some of the interactive features offered on our Site.

**Other Technologies**. Like many websites, we may use standard Internet technology, such as web beacons, site tags, clear GIFs and other similar technologies, to collect and maintain information about your web-surfing activity when you are visiting this Site, other Purdue Global sites as well as other non-Purdue Global sites. We also may include web beacons or pixels in advertisements and promotional e-mail messages to determine whether advertising or messages have been acted upon. The information we obtain in this manner enables us to customize the services we offer our website visitors, to deliver targeted advertisements, and to measure the overall effectiveness of our online advertising, content, programming or other activities.

**Do Not Track Practices.** Some web browsers may transmit "do-not-track" signals to the websites with which the user communicates.  Because of differences in how web browsers incorporate and activate this feature, it is not always clear whether users intend for these signals to be transmitted, or whether they even are aware of them.  Because no industry standard exists concerning what, if anything, websites should do when they receive such signals, Purdue Global currently does not take action in response to these signals.  If and when a final standard is established and accepted, we will reassess how to respond to these signals.

### How We Use the Information We Collect

**In General. We may use information that we collect about you to:**

Deliver the products and services that you have requested; manage your account and provide you with customer support; perform research and analysis about your use of, or interest in, our products, services, or content, or products, services or content offered by others; communicate with you by e-mail, postal mail, telephone and/or mobile devices about products or services that may be of interest to you either from us, other Purdue Global companies or other third parties; develop and display content and advertising tailored to your interests on our Site and other sites; verify your eligibility and deliver prizes in connection with contests and sweepstakes; enforce our terms and conditions; manage our business and perform functions as otherwise described to you at the time of collection.

**Financial information**. We may use financial information or payment method to process payment for any purchases, subscriptions or sales made on our Site, to protect against or identify possible fraudulent transactions, and otherwise as needed to manage our business.

### **With Whom We Share Your Information**

We want you to understand when and with whom we may share personal or other information we have collected about you or your activities on our Site or while using our services.

**Personal information**. We do not share your personal information with others except as indicated below or when we inform you and give you an opportunity to opt out of having your personal information shared. We may share personal information with:

**Authorized service providers** : We may share your personal information with our authorized service providers that perform certain services on our behalf. These services may include fulfilling orders, processing credit card payments, delivering packages, providing customer service and marketing assistance, performing business and sales analysis, supporting our website functionality, and supporting contests, sweepstakes, surveys and other features offered through our website. These service providers may have access to personal information needed to perform their functions but are not permitted to share or use such information for any other purposes.

**Business partners** : When you make purchases, reservations or engage in promotions offered through our Site or our services, we may share personal information with the businesses with which we partner to offer you those products, services, promotions, contests and/or sweepstakes. When you elect to engage in a particular merchant's offer or program, you authorize us to provide your email address and other information to that merchant.

**Selected providers** : From time to time we may share your contact information with selected providers of goods and services that may be of interest to you. If you prefer not to receive information from these providers, you can notify us at any time by emailing to PGPrivacy@purdueglobal.edu.

**Other Purdue Global businesses** : We may share information we collect, including personal information, with the Purdue Global companies. Sharing information with our Purdue Global companies enables us to provide you with information about a variety of products and services that might interest you.

**Other Situations**. We also may disclose your information: In response to a subpoena or similar investigative demand, a court order, or a request for cooperation from a law enforcement or other government agency; to establish or exercise our legal rights; to defend against legal claims; or as otherwise required by law. In such cases, we may raise or waive any legal objection or right available to us, in our sole discretion. When we believe disclosure is appropriate in connection with efforts to investigate, prevent, report or take other action regarding illegal activity, suspected fraud or other wrongdoing; to protect and defend the rights, property or safety of our company, our users, our employees, or others; to comply with applicable law or cooperate with law enforcement; or to enforce our website terms and conditions or other agreements or policies.

We also may disclose your information in connection with a substantial corporate transaction, such as the sale of our business, a divestiture, merger, consolidation, or asset sale, or in the unlikely event of bankruptcy.

Any third parties to whom we may disclose personal information may have their own privacy policies which describe how they use and disclose personal information. Those policies will govern use, handling and disclosure of your personal information once we have shared it with those third parties as described in this Privacy Policy. If you want to learn more about their privacy practices, we encourage you to visit the websites of those third parties. These entities or their servers may be located either inside or outside the United States.

**Aggregated and non-personal information**. We may share aggregated and non-personal information we collect under any of the above circumstances. We may also share it with third parties and other Purdue Global companies to develop and deliver targeted advertising on our websites and on websites of third parties. We may combine non-personal information we collect with additional non-personal information collected from other sources. We also may share aggregated information with third parties, including advisors, advertisers and investors, for the purpose of conducting general business analysis.

### **Third-Party Websites**

There are a number of places on the Site or through our services where you may click on a link to access other websites that do not operate under this Privacy Policy. These third-party websites may independently solicit and collect information, including personal information, from you and, in some instances, provide us with information about your activities on those websites. We recommend that you consult the privacy statements of all third-party websites you visit by clicking on the "privacy" link typically located at the bottom of the webpage you are visiting.

### **User Submissions**

We may provide areas on our Site where you can post information about yourself and others and communicate with others; upload content (e.g. pictures, videos, audio files, etc.); and post comments or reviews of content found on the Site. In addition, such postings may appear on other websites or when searches are executed on the subject of your posting. Also, whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information on publicly-viewable web pages, that information will be publicly available and can be collected and used by others. For example, if you post your email address, you may receive unsolicited messages. We cannot control who reads your posting or what other users may do with the information you voluntarily post, so we encourage you to exercise discretion and caution with respect to your personal information. Once you have posted information, you may not be able to edit or delete such information.

### **Children's Privacy**

Our website is a general audience site, and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13.

### **Visiting Our Site From Outside the United States**

If you are visiting our Site from outside the United States, please be aware that your information may be transferred to, stored, and processed in the United States where our servers are located and our central database is operated. The data protection and other laws of the United States and other countries might not be as comprehensive as those in your country. Please be assured that we seek to take reasonable steps to ensure that your privacy is protected. By using our services, you understand that your information may be transferred to our facilities and those third parties with whom we share it as described in this privacy policy. If you have questions or requests related to the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), please contact us at PGPrivacy@purdueglobal.edu.

### **No Rights of Third Parties**

This Privacy Policy does not create rights enforceable by third parties or require disclosure of any personal information relating to users of the website.

### **Changes to This Privacy Policy**

We will occasionally update this Privacy Policy to reflect changes in our practices and services. When we post changes to this Privacy Policy, we will revise the "Last Updated" date at the top of this Privacy Policy. By continuing to use our Site after we modify this Privacy Policy, you accept the new version of the Privacy Policy. Therefore, it is important that you read this page regularly to ensure you are familiar with the most updated Agreement.  If you do not agree to the changes, you should not continue to use the Site and should instead contact us by emailing PGPrivacy@purdueglobal.edu.

### **How to Contact Us**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or our information-handling practices, or if you would like to request information about our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes, please contact us by email as follows: PGPrivacy@purdueglobal.edu

### **How to Unsubscribe**

If you no longer wish to receive our emails, there is an unsubscribe link located in the footer of all emails that we send.

### **Security**

Purdue Global is concerned with the security of your personal data. To keep that data secure, we restrict unauthorized access through protective policies, procedures, and technical measures. In addition, Purdue Global uses industry standard security protocols and mechanisms to transmit sensitive data such as credit card.

Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal data, we can't guarantee the security of any information you provide us, and you do so at your own risk.

### **Review and Correction**

You may review and update the personal information you have provided to us by contacting us at **PGPrivacy@purdueglobal.edu** or by writing to:

Attn: Information Inquiry or Update  
550 West Van Buren Street, 7th Floor  
Chicago, IL 60607
